Nati Gebregorgis

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

nati.g5684@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +966 559264431

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with experience in using Ruby on Rails on the back-end & React on the front-end. For the past two years, I've developed complex projects using React, JavaScript, & Ruby on Rails. Skilled with debugging & collaborating remotely. Seeking opportunities to utilize my skills & grow as a developer.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Mobile/Responsive Development, Chrome Dev Tools.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

Jan 2022 - Present

Mastered intermediate & advanced topics in full-stack development (including Front-End Development, Rails, Git, & DS&A challenges) while building 15+ full-stack projects both independently & via pair-programming. Some of them are listed below:

- Space Travels (<u>Live Demo</u>)— This is a web application for a company that provides commercial & scientific space travel services. Built with: JavaScript, HTML, React, Redux, & API.
- MovieSpace (<u>Live Demo</u>) This web application is based on an external API. We selected an API that provides data about top-rated movies & then built a web app around it. **Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Webpack & API**.
- <u>Budget App</u> (<u>Live Demo</u>)— This is a web application where you can manage your budget: you have a list of transactions associated with a category so that you can see how much money you spend & on what. **Built with: PostgreSQL, Ruby On Rails, & BootStrap.**
- Riyadh Season (<u>Live Demo</u>)— This website gives users a little insight or an idea of how Saudi Arabia celebrates the Riyadh season annual festival. **Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS & BootStrap.**

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

Feb 2022 – Present

- Mentored 10 junior web developers, providing detailed technical support through over 50 code reviews every month, resulting in a 30% increase in code quality.
- Implemented strategies to help maintain motivation & promote longevity in the program, resulting in a 5% increase in program retention.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE Jan 2022 – Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, & full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, & Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, & daily standups to communicate & collaborate with international remote developers.